nadaguides.com 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy - NADAguides.com

**Notice:**

 _NAG’s Privacy Policy has been updated as of 2-21-2018. Please be aware this update includes a number of significant changes to the previous Privacy Policy, including how we collect your information, how we process online purchases, and how your information may be shared with third parties._

**Introduction**

This Privacy Policy constitutes a legally binding agreement between you and National Appraisal Guides, Inc. (referred to herein as **“NAG”** , **“us”** , or **“we”** ). 

It sets forth how we may collect, use, and disclose your personal data or personally identifiable information ( **“Personal Data”** ) and other information in connection with your use of any NAG website, including without limitation nadaguides.com and nadaguidesstore.com (collectively, the **“Websites”** ); your purchase of any print guidebook, online access subscription, or other NAG product (collectively, the **“Products”** ); and your use of any other NAG services (collectively, and inclusive of all defined terms in this paragraph, the **“Services”** ). 

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, the term “Personal Data” shall include without limitation your name, date of birth, mailing addresses, email addresses, telephone numbers, payment card information, and vehicle identification numbers ( **“VIN”** ). By using the Services, you agree that you have read, understand, and consent to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

**Information You Provide**

_Website Forms_

We may require you to provide us with certain information, and in some cases Personal Data, in order to utilize various forms on our Websites, including without limitation the “new and used car search” form, the dealer quote form, the “best car deals” form, vehicle record search forms, loan qualification forms, payment calculators, the “email this page” form, and the “contact us” form (collectively, **“Website Forms”** ). By inputting your information, you consent to the use of your information, including the sharing of your information with third parties, as necessary to effectuate the purposes of the Website Form where you input such information. In addition to Website Forms, we may occasionally post brief surveys on the Website. By filling out a survey, you consent to the sharing of your responses with third parties. 

_Third Parties_

Additionally, we may provide you with links where you can share information with third parties, including but not limited to insurance providers, car buying/selling services, and social media websites like Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn. The policies and procedures described here do not apply to these websites. We encourage you to review those third parties’ privacy policies, which govern your use of their sites. 

_Online Purchases_

In order to complete a purchase through the Website, including but not limited to purchases through the product store ( **“Product Store”** ), you will be required to enter payment card information and other Personal Data. All online payments are processed through a third party payment processor. In order to better facilitate your use of the Services, including but not limited to by more efficiently processing repeat payments and refunds, we may store payment card information associated with online purchases for up to six months. 

_Telephone Purchases_

You may also purchase Products by telephone. In such cases, we will collect your payment card information over the phone and process your payment ourselves. In order to better facilitate your use of the Services, including but not limited to by more efficiently processing repeat payments and refunds, we may store payment card information associated with telephone purchases for up to six months. 

_Other Information_

We may also collect your telephone number and other information in order to better facilitate your use of the Services. By giving us your telephone number, you expressly consent to receive a phone call or a text message from us. We will not use your telephone number for sales or marketing purposes. For information on how to opt out of telephone communications, see the “How to Opt Out” section below. 

**Information Collected Through Automated Means**

We may automatically collect certain information about your browsing habits, or your device or computer and its capabilities, including but not limited to the operating system, IP address, device carrier, device type, time zone, network status, browser type, browser identifier, location, internet service provider, operating system, pages you visit, referring or exiting pages, and other information that alone or in combination may be used to uniquely identify your device or computer. 

**Cookie Policy**

We use "cookies" on our Websites. Generally, a cookie is a small text file placed on your hard drive by a webpage server. It cannot be executed as code or deliver viruses. It is uniquely yours and can only be read by the website that gave it to you. A cookie saves you time when ordering Products, or requesting information or Services. If you never give us any Personal Data, we only know that someone with your cookie has returned to the Website. You are in charge of deciding whether we know anything about you, but the more you tell us about yourself, the more we can help you find information or Products you want. Cookie technology may be disabled on your browser. 

**Do Not Track**

Because there is no commonly accepted response for Do Not Track signals initiated by browsers, we do not presently respond to them. 

**How We Use Your Information**

In addition to other purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy, we use information collected through NAG Services as follows: 

  * to communicate with you regarding your use of the Services, including your purchases
  * to process your payment information and complete purchases of our Products
  * to effectuate the purpose of a Website Form, including but not limited to determining your eligibility for a loan and providing you with dealer quotes
  * to comply with any and all legal obligations
  * to update our records
  * to comply with any data suppression obligations or requirements
  * for identity verification and fraud detection and/or prevention purposes
  * as otherwise permitted under to this Privacy Policy or as otherwise authorized by you

**Communications You May Receive**

We or our agents, processors, vendors, or subcontractors may contact you or communicate with you via email or telephone communications for the purpose of: 

  * communicating with you regarding your subscriptions or recent purchases
  * sending you newsletters
  * sending you notices required by law or under this Privacy Policy
  * communicating with you regarding promotions
  * responding to your inquiries
  * sending you communications to confirm your identity and for fraud detection and prevention purposes
  * communicating with you as otherwise authorized by you

By providing us (or a third party, through a Website Form) with contact information, you agree to be contacted for the above purposes and any other purposes reasonably necessary to our providing the Services. For more information about how to unsubscribe from certain communications, see “How to Opt Out" below. 

**How We Share Information with Third Parties**

We may disclose your Personal Data and other information with third parties as follows: 

  * with your consent
  * if you complete a third party’s Website Form
  * under applicable law or in response to a subpoena or an order of a court or government agency
  * to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims of an individual or NAG
  * to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of our company, our employees, our users, or others
  * to enforce our agreements and policies
  * if we believe disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud, or other wrongdoing
  * in connection with a corporate change such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or a partial or total sale of our assets
  * to authorized agents, vendors, subcontractors, clients, and partners as necessary for such parties to provide us services
  * as otherwise permitted under this Privacy Policy

**How Your Privacy Is Protected**

We take commercially reasonable steps to ensure information we gather on our Websites is stored in a secure manner. Any payment card information you may provide us online is secured using industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption. While we work hard to protect your privacy, no physical or electronic security system is impenetrable or invulnerable to attack. We cannot and do not guarantee that our systems, or your information, will be secure. 

**Your Advertising Choices**

Advertisers and other third party service providers may collect and use information about your visits to this website and other websites in order to provide advertisements regarding goods and services they feel may be of interest to you. Such marketing practices anonymously track online behaviors in order to deliver “interest-based” advertising. 

We are committed to marketing and advertising transparency, and adhere to the [Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising](https://www.iab.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf). 

If you would like to obtain more information about these advertising practices, please visit the “Understanding Online Advertising” consumer section at the Digital Advertising Alliance's AboutAds.info website here: <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers>. 

To opt-out from many of the larger advertisers’ “interest-based” advertisement tracking, please visit the Digital Advertising Alliance’s consumer choice tool here: [http://optout.aboutads.info/ - !/](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/)

For additional choices in opting out from “interest-based” advertising, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative's opt-out tool here: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/ - !/](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/)

**Special Note About Children**

We adhere to applicable laws and industry codes pertaining to the protection of children's privacy. Our Services are not designed or intended for use by any individual under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect Personal Data from anyone under the age of thirteen 13. If we become aware that we inadvertently collect Personal Data from anyone under this age threshold, we will promptly delete such Personal Data. 

**How to Opt Out**

Users may opt-out of communications from NAG by: 

  * clicking on the unsubscribe link contained in any email communication
  * contacting us via email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
  * contacting us via regular mail at: 

Attn: Customer Support   
National Appraisal Guides   
3200 Park Center Drive, 13th Floor   
Costa Mesa, CA 92626 

**Questions or Complaints**

If you have any questions or complaints regarding our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, or want to exercise your rights to access, review, correct, delete, or object to the processing of Personal Data, contact us via email or mail at the addresses above. We will look into the matter immediately. 

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update, or modify this Privacy Policy by posting such change, update, or modification on our Websites. Any such change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the website. Accordingly, we encourage you to refer to this Privacy Policy on an ongoing basis. This Privacy Policy is current as of the date which appears at the top of this Privacy Policy. We will treat Personal Data in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy under which it was collected, unless we have your consent to treat it differently. By using the Websites or the Services following any Privacy Policy change, you freely and specifically give us your consent to collect, use, transfer, and disclose your Personal Data in the manner specified in the then-current Privacy Policy.
